Bharath Kumar Velugu

Boca Raton, FL,33496, United States

CONTACT INFORMATION:

Mail: <u>bharatyadavvelugu@gmail.com</u>

Mobile: +1 5618875335

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vbharathkumar/

SUMMARY

An Enthusiastic student and a Creative Front-End Developer, UI/UX designer with 3 years of experience in front-end development with the skill of programming to deliver engaging user experience through efficient website development, feature optimization, and relentless debugging.

Expert with skills in requirements definition and code debugging as part of web application development. Innovative and creative in developing fresh designs to meet current and forecasted needs. Works great with technical and non-technical teams to coordinate on-time and quality releases.

EXPERIENCE

SR FRONT END DEVELOPER

Oct 2022 - Aug 2023

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES, HYDERABAD, INDIA

- Develop and implement efficient and effective software solutions to improve business processes and drive productivity.
- Collaborated closely with UX/UI designers and back-end developers to translate design mockups and requirements into functional, responsive web applications.

PROGRAMMER ANALYST

Dec 2020 - Sep 2022

COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS, HYDERABAD, INDIA

- Designed and developed intuitive and user-friendly web interfaces using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript libraries and frameworks such as React, Angular.
- Worked in an agile environment as a Front End/ UI developer. Developed responsive web pages, Implemented SEO and Accessibility.
- Written code with cross browser compatibility (Mozilla, Safari, Chrome).

EDUCATION

Master's in computer science

Aug 2023 (Expected)

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY, BOCA RATON, FLORIDA

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communication Engineering Jun 2016 - Mar 2020

RGMCET, KURNOOL, ANDHRA PRADESH, INDIA

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

MERN Stack React Node Ecommerce

2022

Udemy - https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-be4e6595-7c6f-48e2-bbcb-20d4e9976737/

Agile Product Management

2021

Udemy - https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-ce6e5268-2fa6-4c2e-bead-738efcd12195

Web Design Fundamentals

2021

Udemy - https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-fddfb619-40fc-430e-8b59-318e2e7c3149/

Honors

- Honored with the Elite Badge of Honor by NPTEL.org for achieving an 80 percent score in the Python programming examination.
- Attained an Advanced Level Grade in the English Proficiency Test administered by the STEP-HINDU group at a national level.